The term flat file encompasses a wide family of
平面文件这个术语包含众多
files with similar core traits then some slight differences.
具有相似核心特质但又稍有差异的文件
Let's start with the core traits.
我们从核心特质开始讲起
Flat files contain tabular data in plain text format with one data record
平面文件包含纯文本格式的表格数据
per line in each record or line having one or more fields.
每行一个数据记录 每个记录或每行有一个或多个字段
These fields are separated by delimiters,
这些字段用分隔符隔开
like commas for example,
比如逗号
as you can see on the left side of the screen.
正如你在页面左侧见到的
Software like Pandas or spreadsheet applications like Google sheets,
Pandas 等软件或 Google Sheets 等电子表格应用
which you can see on the right side of the screen here.
页面右侧可见
Use these cues in the data to understand how
利用数据中的这些线索 了解如何
to represent the data inside their respective programs.
表达各自程序内部的数据
So both of these sides of the screen are actually
所以页面两侧实际上
the same file just opened in different programs,
是相同的文件 只不过是在不同的程序中打开而已
the text editor and a spreadsheet program.
即文本编辑器和电子表格程序
And because they're in plain text,
由于它们是纯文本格式
flat files are human readable.
人们可以自行阅读平面文件
So again, plain text,
所以 重复一遍 纯文本
one record per line,
每行一条记录
each line having fields,
每行都有若干字段
delimiters separating each field,
每个字段用分隔符隔开
moving on to the slight differences.
继续谈谈细微差别
First and foremost, the delimiters can vary.
首先 分隔符各不相同
Most often, commas are used,
逗号是最常用的
which are called CSV files,
被称为 CSV 文件
or comma separated values,
或逗号分隔值
like this file on the left.
像左侧的这个文件一样
Sometimes, other ones are use like tabs in
有时候 也会用到其他分隔符 比如
a TSV or tab separated values file, which you can see here.
TSV 或 制表符分隔值文件中的制表符 你可以在这里见到
This is the flat file you'll use in this lesson.
这就是你们将在这堂课中用到的平面文件
Sometimes, the delimiters are spaces or even semi-colons.
有时候 分隔符是空格 甚至是分号
All of these files show up the same way in a spreadsheet program,
但所有这些文件都是以相同方式显示在电子表格程序中的
like Google sheets on the right here though.
比如右侧的 Google Sheets
There's also no standardization that's adhered to amongst flat files as a whole,
整个平面文件中并没有遵循的标准
and even within the individual file types.
甚至在个别文件类型内也是如此
There are a bunch of little quirks.
还有许多奇怪的点
The major one being some files having
主要的一个就是有些文件
single or double quotes around each field entry, like this.
在每个字段条目有单引号或双引号 就像这样
Here, double quotes are used.
在这里 使用的是双引号
Okay, so let's talk about specific file types.
好的 我们来谈谈具体的文件类型
CSV and TSV files,
CSV 和 TSV 文件
if valid and structure, are always flat.
如果具有有效结构 那就始终是平面文件
CSV on the left,
CSV 文件在左侧
TSV on the right..txt files,
TSV 文件在右侧 .txt 文件
as you can see in the top of this header here,.txt,
正如你在标题顶部见到的 .txt
can be flat files too,
也可以是平面文件
if they adhere to the tabular one record per line with delimiters rules of flat files.
如果它们遵循平面文件的制表规则 每行一条记录用分隔符隔开的话
But text files don't have to be flat files,
但文本文件不一定是平面文件
they can just be a blob of text like,
它们只是像文本的 blob
the Roger Ebert review text for the movie, Casablanca.
Roger Ebert 对影片《卡萨布兰卡》的影评文本
You'll see this variation of a.txt file later in the lesson.
本课后面你将会见到 .txt 版本
In contrast, Excel files which are tabular aren't flat.
相比之下 属于表格文件的 Excel 文件并非平面文件
Excel has this data in a zipped collection of XML files, another file format.
Excel 将这些数据放在一个压缩的 XML 文件集中 这是另一种文件格式
In an Excel files original zip format,
在一个原始压缩格式的 Excel 文件中
it's not human readable.
人们是不可能自己读懂的
But once unzipped, the XML is,
但一旦解压缩 XML 就是可以读懂的
but it's definitely not as easy as a flat file.
但肯定不像平面文件那样轻松
So, flat files have their advantages and disadvantages.
所以 平面文件有利有弊
They're simple human readable and software that can read
它们很简单 人们读的懂
and write text files which all flat files are is ubiquitous.
而且很多软件能够读写属于平面文件的文本文件
A simple text editor like sublime being one example.
像 sublime 这样的简单的文本编辑器就是一个很好的例子
Some disadvantage is our lack of standards,
缺点包括我们缺乏标准
lack of integrity, and sometimes, massive data redundancy.
缺乏完整度 有时候 还包括大量数据冗余
These will become more clear as we introduce other file types later in the lesson.
当我们在本课后面介绍其他文件类型时 这些缺点就会更加明显了